Tears Abound as Disney's Unpaid Experts Are Crowned
"My American dream was to go to Walt Disney World," says Aena Drone, who came to the US from Pakistan as a child.
It's safe to say that as of now, she has long surpassed her dream.
Why is that? The 36-year-old is one of 14 people selected from 10,000 applicants who are joining 28 returning members as the 2024 Disney Parks Moms Panel.
This panel is a group of volunteer ‘Disney experts’ who assist travelers in planning their Disney vacations.
To encourage honesty, none of the panelists are paid, and their workload is to answer about 15 questions a week.
According to a press release from Disney, the panelists dedicate their free time to answering questions like where to find Disney World's private nursing rooms and all those hidden Mickeys.
For this, each panel member gets a free, five-night stay for four people at the resort.
These Disney superfans have a combined total of 714 Disney vacations under their belts.
"When I was young and my parents told me that I was moving to America from Pakistan, it was scary.
But they also told me Mickey Mouse lived in America because he was my hero," says Drone.
When interviewed for this report, the stay-at-home mom of two boys became so overwhelmed that she started to cry," noted the reporter.
Tamela Hansen of Alabama, who has visited Disney World at least 100 times, said she had applied to be a panelist 12 times before she was finally selected.
Almost all of the new panelists, who serve in the year-long contractor role, said they felt they were part of the Disney family.
Three of the panelists are men, two are childless, and each has their own area of expertise. Some are already hard at work answering enthusiastic Disney travelers.